Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College records from administrator Nina Mikhalevsky, 1905-2000 MVC0042.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College records from administrator Nina Mikhalevsky
1905-2000
1980-2000
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mikhalevsky, Nina
MVC0042.RG
4.5 Linear Feet 9 document boxes
This collection contains meeting minutes and administrative files belonging to Dr. Nina Mikhalevsky, a professor and administrator at Mount Vernon College for over 20 years. Mikhalevsky held many positions at Mount Vernon College including chair of the Liberal Studies department, dean of students, and director of the Elizabeth J. Somers Women's Leadership Program, among others. The materials in this collection range in date from 1905-2000, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1980-2000.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Meeting minutes and Administrative files.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Mount Vernon Seminary and College archives were acquired by GWU upon merger with Mount Vernon College. The collection was transferred to the Foggy Bottom campus in 2009.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Nina Mikhalevsky joined Mount Vernon College's faculty in 1979 and remained at the college for two decades. She was the first director of the honors program, chair of the Liberal Studies Department, presiding officer of the faculty, dean of students and campus life, director of the Elizabeth J. Somers Women's Leadership Program, and assistant dean of The George Washington University's Columbian College of Arts and Sciences. She is also the author of the book, Dear Daughters: A history of Mount Vernon Seminary and College, which was published in 2001.
Dr. Mikhalevsky holds a Ph.D. (1981) and an M.A. (1977) in philosophy from Georgetown University, as well as a B.A. (1974) in philosophy from Boston University.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes and administrative files from the office of Dr. Nina Mikhalevsky, a professor and administrator who held various positions at Mount Vernon College for two decades beginning in 1979. The materials in this collection range in date from 1905-2000, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1980-2000.
Women's colleges; Board of Trustees; Meetings; Women -- Education; Mikhalevsky, Nina; Mount Vernon College
- Meeting minutes, 1991-2000; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains meeting minutes from the Mount Vernon College Board of Trustees, The Council for Mount Vernon, Mount Vernon College faculty, and various Board committees. The materials range in date from 1991-2000.
  - Board of Trustees binder, 1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1995; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board meetings binder part 1, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board meetings binder part 2, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Council for Mount Vernon Fall meeting, 1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Council for Mount Vernon meeting minutes, 1999-2000; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1998-1999; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Finance Committee meeting minutes, 1993-1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Finance/Development Committee meeting minutes, 1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Administrative files, 1905-2000; 1980-2000; Series 2
  This series contains adminiatrative files including event files, programs and pamphlets, and files regarding various groups and committees related to Mount Vernon College. The materials in this series date from 1905-2000, with the bulk of the material dating from 1980-2000.
  - Academic Affairs, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Committee, 1999-2000; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Committee, 2001; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumnae Relations, 1993; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alumnae Relations donor information, 1989; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American University papers, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Archives handouts, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Baccalaureate address, 1985-1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Betty Friedan, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Buzz; The Toilet Tattler, Commuter St. News, 1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Campus plan, 2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Celebration of Women's Education, 1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Certificate of exemption, 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Colonial Inauguration and MVC pin, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commencement, 1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commencement, 1988; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commencement, 1988; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Commencement, 1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Commencement, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence re: Victoria Schuck memorial, 1998; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Council for Mount Vernon first meeting, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D.C. Chamber of Commerce, 1992-1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - D.C. Commission for Women, 1988; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - D.C. Geographic Alliance, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Diners Club, 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Distinguished Alumnae Award, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Economic Club of Washington, 1991-1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Elizabeth J. Somers Center, 1998; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Enrollment statistics, 1952-1963; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Eureka Communities, 1993-1994; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - European tour, 1905; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty and staff, 1958-1966; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty and staff photos, 1980-1999; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Former trustee list, 1992; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University, 1992-1994; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Georgetown University, 1993; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GW Business; The Centuries Campaign for Mount Vernon, 1998-2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Guest book, 1992; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Inauguration, 1992; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hand Chapel history, 1970; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Honors courses, 1984-1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Leadership group, 1998-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Colin Powell re: Mount Vernon Tennis Classic, 1988; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lists - student officers, 1954-1969; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Loose administrative records, 1996-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Marjorie Merriweather Post - biography, 1977; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Memos to/from, 1998-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Merriweather Post binder part 1, 1986-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Merriweather Post binder part 2, 1986-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Middle States final report, 1998; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Middle States; MSA report and MVC response, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Millenium seminars, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mount Vernon College Board, 1997; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mount Vernon College brochures, ca. 1990s; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mount Vernon College Bulletin, 1975; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mount Vernon College bulletins and programs, 1989-1996; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mount Vernon College convocation and awards ceremonies programs, 1998; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mount Vernon College empty diploma holder, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mount Vernon College and GWU miscellaneous brochures, 1990-2002; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mount Vernon College and GWU publications, 1997-1998; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mount Vernon College loose administrative material, ca. 1980s; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mount Vernon College miscellaneous documents, 1969-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Mount Vernon College miscellaneous event files, 1997-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mount Vernon College miscellaneous events programs, 1986-1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mount Vernon College miscellaneous flyers, 1996-1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mount Vernon College miscellaneous programs and publications, 1953-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mount Vernon College New Programs, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mount Vernon College photos, 1988-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mount Vernon College photos, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mount Vernon College Strategic Plan, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Mount Vernon College student handbook, 1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary miscellaneous documents, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary and College archives, 1992-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mount Vernon Today, 2001-2002; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - MVC Alma Mater, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - MVC website (old), 1991-2001; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Notes to file, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Office of Development, 1990; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oral History Project, 1995; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - President Evans resignation, 1990; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Recipients, 1984-1993; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Record, 1986; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Schedule of classes and campus directories, 1997-1998; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Somers biography manuscript, 1999; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Strategic Plan GWU/MVC, 1998; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Student forwarding addresses, 1998; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Student Government Association, 1996-1998; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "The Careful Beginning of a Big Idea", 2002-2003; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Transition Committee Report, 1997; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Women and Power Leadership Programs, 2000; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Women's College Coalition 1, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Women's College Coalition 2, 1993-1994; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Women's College Coalition 3, 1980-1982; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Women's College Coalition 4, 1992-1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Women's College Coalition 5, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Women's College Coalition 6, 1993-1994; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Women's Forum, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Women's History Week, 1986; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Women in Politics concept papers and LAGs notes, 1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Women in Politics correspondence, 1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Women in Politics program and dinner agenda, 1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)